<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Index on North Brooklyn Angels</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in Index on North Brooklyn Angels</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Charity Spotlight: North Brooklyn Angels</title><link>/in-the-news/2021/01/charity-spotlight-north-brooklyn-angels/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/in-the-news/2021/01/charity-spotlight-north-brooklyn-angels/</guid><description>In this our second Charity Spotlight, and the first of 2021, we continue our focus on the critical and tragic issue of food insecurity and an organization that has been tenaciously battling hunger in our local community since they were formed in 2016. The North Brooklyn Angels (Angels) are a volunteer-powered, hyper-local grassroots non-profit working to fight hunger, food insecurity, and poverty in our community.
The Angels began their service in June 2017, powered with a 40 ft.</description></item><item><title>We Met Them in the Depths of the Pandemic. How Are They Doing Now?</title><link>/in-the-news/2020/12/we-met-them-in-the-depths-of-the-pandemic.-how-are-they-doing-now/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/in-the-news/2020/12/we-met-them-in-the-depths-of-the-pandemic.-how-are-they-doing-now/</guid><description>Checking in with the blues bassist, the homeless student, the hipster priest and the lesbian couple who survived the Spanish flu and the Holocaust.</description></item><item><title>How Community Groups Plan To Provide A "Dignified Thanksgiving" In North Brooklyn</title><link>/in-the-news/2020/11/how-community-groups-plan-to-provide-a-dignified-thanksgiving-in-north-brooklyn/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/in-the-news/2020/11/how-community-groups-plan-to-provide-a-dignified-thanksgiving-in-north-brooklyn/</guid><description>Amid a holiday season unlike any other in the last century, one North Brooklyn community organization is making sure their neighbors in need have somewhere to get a hot meal on Turkey Day.
The North Brooklyn Angels, in partnership with a bevy of other community groups, will bring 400 meals to those in need this Thanksgiving, the group announced last week. Organizers say the offerings will be a more elevated version of what the Angels usually offer, to allow for a “dignified Thanksgiving” during a challenging time.</description></item><item><title>North Brooklyn Angels Partner With Restaurants To Feed Those In Need</title><link>/in-the-news/2020/06/north-brooklyn-angels-partner-with-restaurants-to-feed-those-in-need/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/in-the-news/2020/06/north-brooklyn-angels-partner-with-restaurants-to-feed-those-in-need/</guid><description>NEW YORK (WCB 880) — Brooklyn kitchen workers are still working and people who need meals are still being fed thanks to an innovative program that was born during the coronavirus pandemic.
Jimmy’s Kitchen in Greenpoint is one of those popular neighborhood spots that had to close to the public because of the virus. But, that’s doesn’t mean the kitchen isn’t humming.
WCBS 880’s Mike Sugerman reports staff is still showing up every day to serve a new customer base with the help of the North Brooklyn Angels.</description></item><item><title>North Brooklyn Angels Feed The Front Lines While Keeping Local Business Alive</title><link>/in-the-news/2020/04/north-brooklyn-angels-feed-the-front-lines-while-keeping-local-business-alive/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/in-the-news/2020/04/north-brooklyn-angels-feed-the-front-lines-while-keeping-local-business-alive/</guid><description>A group of north Brooklyn do-gooders has ramped up their neighborly efforts during the coronavirus pandemic, becoming a lifeline not only to their neighbors in need but also to the staff of hard-hit Woodhull Hospital. While keeping up its regular acts of altruism, the North Brooklyn Angels have devised a system which provides the workers at Woodhull with three square meals a day from Jimmy&amp;rsquo;s Diner. This, in turn, keeps the beloved Greenpoint eatery &amp;mdash; which previously shut its doors due to the pandemic &amp;mdash; up and running.</description></item><item><title>North Brooklyn Mobile Soup Kitchen Adjusts to Pandemic, Grows Its Support</title><link>/in-the-news/2020/04/north-brooklyn-mobile-soup-kitchen-adjusts-to-pandemic-grows-its-support/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/in-the-news/2020/04/north-brooklyn-mobile-soup-kitchen-adjusts-to-pandemic-grows-its-support/</guid><description>Volunteers formed a human assembly line in the basement of a Williamsburg church on a recent morning, donning N95 and surgical face masks and sanitized latex gloves as they filled to-go containers with meals.
It was a seemingly normal operation for the North Brooklyn Angels, a group that has been feeding Williamsburg and Greenpoint for about three years, but with the restrictions of the coronavirus binding them, the non-profit had to adjust to packing hundreds more meals, creating a network to feed local health care workers and making sure every step of the operation was safe for everyone involved.</description></item><item><title>How to Help in a Pandemic: Ask Before You Donate 1,000 Pizzas</title><link>/in-the-news/2020/04/how-to-help-in-a-pandemic-ask-before-you-donate-1000-pizzas/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/in-the-news/2020/04/how-to-help-in-a-pandemic-ask-before-you-donate-1000-pizzas/</guid><description>A Brooklyn priest learned to cut through the red tape after Hurricane Sandy. He has lessons for us.</description></item><item><title>Are food trucks the future? Fighting food insecurity and gentrification one stop at a time</title><link>/in-the-news/2019/08/are-food-trucks-the-future-fighting-food-insecurity-and-gentrification-one-stop-at-a-time/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/in-the-news/2019/08/are-food-trucks-the-future-fighting-food-insecurity-and-gentrification-one-stop-at-a-time/</guid><description>North Brooklyn Angels prove neighbors helping neighbors is a model for fighting hunger in America</description></item><item><title>Soup kitchen on wheels named 'Angelmobile' serves North Brooklyn's poor</title><link>/in-the-news/2018/06/soup-kitchen-on-wheels-named-angelmobile-serves-north-brooklyns-poor/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/in-the-news/2018/06/soup-kitchen-on-wheels-named-angelmobile-serves-north-brooklyns-poor/</guid><description>GREENPOINT, Brooklyn (WABC) &amp;ndash; Food trucks are a staple of the fast-paced New York City lifestyle, but one Brooklyn food truck does more for the community than dishing out quick and delicious meals.
The &amp;ldquo;Angelmobile&amp;rdquo; is a sort of a &amp;ldquo;soup kitchen on wheels,&amp;rdquo; said Neil Sheen, co-founder of the nonprofit North Brooklyn Angels.
Originally, the North Brooklyn Angels served the Bedford-Stuyvesant community with a brick-and-mortar soup kitchen, St.</description></item><item><title>Neil Sheehan: Greenpoint native provides meals with wheels</title><link>/in-the-news/2018/02/neil-sheehan-greenpoint-native-provides-meals-with-wheels/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/in-the-news/2018/02/neil-sheehan-greenpoint-native-provides-meals-with-wheels/</guid><description>The idea that some people go to bed without a hot meal just didn&amp;rsquo;t sit right with Neil Sheehan.
&amp;ldquo;People need to eat. And helping someone eat, whether it&amp;rsquo;s with your family sitting down or with your friends or with your neighbors, it&amp;rsquo;s a gesture where people smile, they&amp;rsquo;re nourished and it creates good will,&amp;rdquo; Sheehan said.
Nourishing people&amp;rsquo;s bodies while also nourishing his native Greenpoint has always been Sheehan&amp;rsquo;s top priority.</description></item><item><title>Angel Babies Project</title><link>/angel-babies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/angel-babies/</guid><description>Showing the love to area families facing economic hardship is what the Angel Babies project does, several times a year!
Responding to community need and opportunities made possible by local partnerships and volunteer support, Angel Babies elevates our vision of &amp;ldquo;neighbors helping neighbors&amp;rdquo; as we mount big volunteer-driven giveaway events to local, new and expectant families who are in need of resources.</description></item><item><title>Donate</title><link>/donate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/donate/</guid><description>By donating money and sponsoring a meal, you embody our central mission of neighbors helping neighbors. Our grassroots mission is to sustain the ability to serve up to 2,000 meals a week.
$4,000 provides a week of meals to neighbors in need $800 provides a healthy and nutritious lunch for 200 $80 provides a week of lunches for a family of four $4 provides a hot and healthy lunch for a neighbor Donate using PayPal Support the North Brooklyn Angels.</description></item><item><title>Get Involved</title><link>/get-involved/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/get-involved/</guid><description>Our goal is to be the place where newer &amp;amp; long term residents come together in support of feeding insecure neighbors in volunteer projects which aid members of our community struggling with economic change. Serving meals is only the beginning…
Volunteer! North Brooklyn Angels is 95% volunteer-powered! Everything from driving the truck to cooking the meals is done by amazing volunteers.</description></item><item><title>Leadership</title><link>/about-us/leadership/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about-us/leadership/</guid><description>STAFF Kendra Chiu
Executive Director Brooklyn native Kendra Chiu brings over 12 years of experience in nonprofit work, volunteer organizing, and education to the North Brooklyn Angels. Before joining the Angels, Kendra was the Senior Director of Grants and Communications at Outreach, a behavioral health not-for-profit that provides treatment and training services throughout the greater New York Metropolitan area. At Outreach, she grew to oversee the acquisition and management of philanthropic and government grants, communications, program evaluation, and government relations.</description></item><item><title>Meals</title><link>/meals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/meals/</guid><description>North Brooklyn Angels aims to cook &amp;amp; serve 1,500 meals per week to combat the food insecure in our community. Each day, our Angelmobile fleet (so far, two vehicles!) currently serves, on average, 300 meals, depending on the site and the weather. Volunteers prep and serve all the food served in our community meals.
Meals are available on a first come, first served basis and may all be distributed within 15-20 minutes (give or take) upon arrival, depending on the weather, holiday season, and other variables.</description></item><item><title>Neighbors Giving Thanks</title><link>/thanksgiving/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/thanksgiving/</guid><description>Every holiday season, North Brooklyn Angels hosts a multi-day event called Neighbors Giving Thanks. The goal is to bring a joyous and dignified Thanksgiving experience to our neighbors in Greenpoint/Williamsburg who may not have a place, or the means, to celebrate.
To make this happen, we need your help!</description></item></channel></rss>