<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Index on North Brooklyn Angels</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in Index on North Brooklyn Angels</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Charity Spotlight: North Brooklyn Angels</title><link>/in-the-news/2021/01/charity-spotlight-north-brooklyn-angels/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/in-the-news/2021/01/charity-spotlight-north-brooklyn-angels/</guid><description>In this our second Charity Spotlight, and the first of 2021, we continue our focus on the critical and tragic issue of food insecurity and an organization that has been tenaciously battling hunger in our local community since they were formed in 2016. The North Brooklyn Angels (Angels) are a volunteer-powered, hyper-local grassroots non-profit working to fight hunger, food insecurity, and poverty in our community.
The Angels began their service in June 2017, powered with a 40 ft.</description></item><item><title>We Met Them in the Depths of the Pandemic. How Are They Doing Now?</title><link>/in-the-news/2020/12/we-met-them-in-the-depths-of-the-pandemic.-how-are-they-doing-now/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/in-the-news/2020/12/we-met-them-in-the-depths-of-the-pandemic.-how-are-they-doing-now/</guid><description>Checking in with the blues bassist, the homeless student, the hipster priest and the lesbian couple who survived the Spanish flu and the Holocaust.</description></item><item><title>How Community Groups Plan To Provide A "Dignified Thanksgiving" In North Brooklyn</title><link>/in-the-news/2020/11/how-community-groups-plan-to-provide-a-dignified-thanksgiving-in-north-brooklyn/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/in-the-news/2020/11/how-community-groups-plan-to-provide-a-dignified-thanksgiving-in-north-brooklyn/</guid><description>Amid a holiday season unlike any other in the last century, one North Brooklyn community organization is making sure their neighbors in need have somewhere to get a hot meal on Turkey Day.
The North Brooklyn Angels, in partnership with a bevy of other community groups, will bring 400 meals to those in need this Thanksgiving, the group announced last week. Organizers say the offerings will be a more elevated version of what the Angels usually offer, to allow for a “dignified Thanksgiving” during a challenging time.</description></item><item><title>North Brooklyn Angels Partner With Restaurants To Feed Those In Need</title><link>/in-the-news/2020/06/north-brooklyn-angels-partner-with-restaurants-to-feed-those-in-need/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/in-the-news/2020/06/north-brooklyn-angels-partner-with-restaurants-to-feed-those-in-need/</guid><description>NEW YORK (WCB 880) — Brooklyn kitchen workers are still working and people who need meals are still being fed thanks to an innovative program that was born during the coronavirus pandemic.
Jimmy’s Kitchen in Greenpoint is one of those popular neighborhood spots that had to close to the public because of the virus. But, that’s doesn’t mean the kitchen isn’t humming.
WCBS 880’s Mike Sugerman reports staff is still showing up every day to serve a new customer base with the help of the North Brooklyn Angels.</description></item><item><title>North Brooklyn Angels Feed The Front Lines While Keeping Local Business Alive</title><link>/in-the-news/2020/04/north-brooklyn-angels-feed-the-front-lines-while-keeping-local-business-alive/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/in-the-news/2020/04/north-brooklyn-angels-feed-the-front-lines-while-keeping-local-business-alive/</guid><description>A group of north Brooklyn do-gooders has ramped up their neighborly efforts during the coronavirus pandemic, becoming a lifeline not only to their neighbors in need but also to the staff of hard-hit Woodhull Hospital. While keeping up its regular acts of altruism, the North Brooklyn Angels have devised a system which provides the workers at Woodhull with three square meals a day from Jimmy&amp;rsquo;s Diner. This, in turn, keeps the beloved Greenpoint eatery &amp;mdash; which previously shut its doors due to the pandemic &amp;mdash; up and running.</description></item><item><title>North Brooklyn Mobile Soup Kitchen Adjusts to Pandemic, Grows Its Support</title><link>/in-the-news/2020/04/north-brooklyn-mobile-soup-kitchen-adjusts-to-pandemic-grows-its-support/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/in-the-news/2020/04/north-brooklyn-mobile-soup-kitchen-adjusts-to-pandemic-grows-its-support/</guid><description>Volunteers formed a human assembly line in the basement of a Williamsburg church on a recent morning, donning N95 and surgical face masks and sanitized latex gloves as they filled to-go containers with meals.
It was a seemingly normal operation for the North Brooklyn Angels, a group that has been feeding Williamsburg and Greenpoint for about three years, but with the restrictions of the coronavirus binding them, the non-profit had to adjust to packing hundreds more meals, creating a network to feed local health care workers and making sure every step of the operation was safe for everyone involved.</description></item><item><title>How to Help in a Pandemic: Ask Before You Donate 1,000 Pizzas</title><link>/in-the-news/2020/04/how-to-help-in-a-pandemic-ask-before-you-donate-1000-pizzas/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/in-the-news/2020/04/how-to-help-in-a-pandemic-ask-before-you-donate-1000-pizzas/</guid><description>A Brooklyn priest learned to cut through the red tape after Hurricane Sandy. He has lessons for us.</description></item><item><title>Are food trucks the future? Fighting food insecurity and gentrification one stop at a time</title><link>/in-the-news/2019/08/are-food-trucks-the-future-fighting-food-insecurity-and-gentrification-one-stop-at-a-time/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/in-the-news/2019/08/are-food-trucks-the-future-fighting-food-insecurity-and-gentrification-one-stop-at-a-time/</guid><description>North Brooklyn Angels prove neighbors helping neighbors is a model for fighting hunger in America</description></item><item><title>Soup kitchen on wheels named 'Angelmobile' serves North Brooklyn's poor</title><link>/in-the-news/2018/06/soup-kitchen-on-wheels-named-angelmobile-serves-north-brooklyns-poor/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/in-the-news/2018/06/soup-kitchen-on-wheels-named-angelmobile-serves-north-brooklyns-poor/</guid><description>GREENPOINT, Brooklyn (WABC) &amp;ndash; Food trucks are a staple of the fast-paced New York City lifestyle, but one Brooklyn food truck does more for the community than dishing out quick and delicious meals.
The &amp;ldquo;Angelmobile&amp;rdquo; is a sort of a &amp;ldquo;soup kitchen on wheels,&amp;rdquo; said Neil Sheen, co-founder of the nonprofit North Brooklyn Angels.
Originally, the North Brooklyn Angels served the Bedford-Stuyvesant community with a brick-and-mortar soup kitchen, St. John&amp;rsquo;s Bread of Life on Lexington Avenue, but in order to reach more people in need, they started thinking outside the box.</description></item><item><title>Neil Sheehan: Greenpoint native provides meals with wheels</title><link>/in-the-news/2018/02/neil-sheehan-greenpoint-native-provides-meals-with-wheels/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/in-the-news/2018/02/neil-sheehan-greenpoint-native-provides-meals-with-wheels/</guid><description>The idea that some people go to bed without a hot meal just didn&amp;rsquo;t sit right with Neil Sheehan.
&amp;ldquo;People need to eat. And helping someone eat, whether it&amp;rsquo;s with your family sitting down or with your friends or with your neighbors, it&amp;rsquo;s a gesture where people smile, they&amp;rsquo;re nourished and it creates good will,&amp;rdquo; Sheehan said.
Nourishing people&amp;rsquo;s bodies while also nourishing his native Greenpoint has always been Sheehan&amp;rsquo;s top priority.</description></item><item><title>Angel Babies</title><link>/angel-babies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/angel-babies/</guid><description>Responding to community need and opportunities made possible by local partnerships and volunteer support, Angel Babies elevates our vision of “neighbors helping neighbors” as we mount big volunteer-driven giveaway events to local, new and expectant families who are in need of resources.
Each time a campaign is ignited, for a few weeks, North Brooklyn businesses, schools, bars, cafes, and large apartment buildings sign on to host donation collections for this incredible giveaway event, netting thousands of Angel Babies donations!</description></item><item><title>Donate</title><link>/donate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/donate/</guid><description>Neighbors Giving Thanks 2025 Support the North Brooklyn Angels. North Brooklyn Angels (legal name: North Brooklyn Coalition of Neighbors Helping Neighbors, Inc.) is a 501(c)(3) and all donations are tax deductible. EIN 81-4576973​
North Brooklyn Angels has always been here for our neighbors - in ordinary times and extraordinary ones. Our volunteer-powered model quietly expands and contracts as the community needs, built on years of relationships and a belief that showing up matters.</description></item><item><title>FAQs</title><link>/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/faq/</guid><description>For Volunteering Who can volunteer? We welcome our community to come and help us in our kitchen, serve meals from our Angelmobile, drive our fleet of mobile soup kitchen vehicles, support our seasonal Angel Babies events, our brand new Little Angels program, and more! Signing up for our bi-weekly newsletter will let you know about our regular weekly shifts as well as micro-but-crucial opportunities for volunteering.
How do I sign up?</description></item><item><title>Get Involved</title><link>/get-involved/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/get-involved/</guid><description>Every day, North Brooklyn Angels serves hundreds of hot meals to neighbors facing food insecurity across North Brooklyn. We bring together newer and long-term residents in meaningful volunteer work that supports community members navigating economic challenges. Serving meals is just the beginning of building stronger neighborhoods together.
Jump In: Start Volunteering Today North Brooklyn Angels is 95% volunteer-powered! From driving our mobile soup kitchens to packaging meals and distributing clothing to families in need, our amazing volunteers make it all possible.</description></item><item><title>Greenpoint Community Yoga</title><link>/yoga/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/yoga/</guid><description>History &amp;amp; Mission of Greenpoint Community Yoga Greenpoint Community Yoga was founded in February 2024 as a way to bring affordable and accessible yoga classes to the community while supporting North Brooklyn Angels.
We offer a monthly series of yoga classes, sound baths, and more. All classes are led by certified instructors and we welcome students at any experience level. It’s $10 to register and all proceeds go to North Brooklyn Angels.</description></item><item><title>Leadership</title><link>/about-us/leadership/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about-us/leadership/</guid><description>STAFF Kendra Chiu
Executive Director Brooklyn native Kendra Chiu brings over 12 years of experience in nonprofit work, volunteer organizing, and education to the North Brooklyn Angels. Before joining the Angels, Kendra was the Senior Director of Grants and Communications at Outreach, a behavioral health not-for-profit that provides treatment and training services throughout the greater New York Metropolitan area. At Outreach, she grew to oversee the acquisition and management of philanthropic and government grants, communications, program evaluation, and government relations.</description></item><item><title>Little Angels FAQ</title><link>/little-angels/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/little-angels/faq/</guid><description>What kind of gently used donation items is Little Angels currently accepting? Our storefront is small with limited capacity. At this time we are only accepting nursing, infant and toddler gear. Things like, breast pumps, car seats, bassinets, etc.
How does Little Angels determine what families to enroll? With the intent of &amp;ldquo;neighbors helping neighbors,&amp;rdquo; we are focusing our Family Outreach specifically within Brooklyn Community District 1 (Greenpoint, Williamsburg and eventually Bushwick).</description></item><item><title>Meals</title><link>/meals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/meals/</guid><description>North Brooklyn Angels aims to cook &amp;amp; serve 2,000 meals per week to neighbors experiencing food insecurity in our community. Each weekday, our Angelmobile fleet (so far, three vehicles!) currently serves, on average, 300 meals, depending on the site and the weather. Volunteers prep and serve all the food served in our community meals.
Meals are available on a first come, first served basis and may all be distributed within 15-20 minutes (give or take) upon arrival, depending on the weather, holiday season, and other variables.</description></item></channel></rss>