<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Brooklyn Paper on North Brooklyn Angels</title><link>/source/brooklyn-paper/</link><description>Recent content in Brooklyn Paper on North Brooklyn Angels</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 22:52:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/source/brooklyn-paper/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How Community Groups Plan To Provide A "Dignified Thanksgiving" In North Brooklyn</title><link>/in-the-news/2020/11/how-community-groups-plan-to-provide-a-dignified-thanksgiving-in-north-brooklyn/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/in-the-news/2020/11/how-community-groups-plan-to-provide-a-dignified-thanksgiving-in-north-brooklyn/</guid><description>Amid a holiday season unlike any other in the last century, one North Brooklyn community organization is making sure their neighbors in need have somewhere to get a hot meal on Turkey Day.
The North Brooklyn Angels, in partnership with a bevy of other community groups, will bring 400 meals to those in need this Thanksgiving, the group announced last week. Organizers say the offerings will be a more elevated version of what the Angels usually offer, to allow for a “dignified Thanksgiving” during a challenging time.</description></item><item><title>North Brooklyn Angels Feed The Front Lines While Keeping Local Business Alive</title><link>/in-the-news/2020/04/north-brooklyn-angels-feed-the-front-lines-while-keeping-local-business-alive/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/in-the-news/2020/04/north-brooklyn-angels-feed-the-front-lines-while-keeping-local-business-alive/</guid><description>A group of north Brooklyn do-gooders has ramped up their neighborly efforts during the coronavirus pandemic, becoming a lifeline not only to their neighbors in need but also to the staff of hard-hit Woodhull Hospital. While keeping up its regular acts of altruism, the North Brooklyn Angels have devised a system which provides the workers at Woodhull with three square meals a day from Jimmy&amp;rsquo;s Diner. This, in turn, keeps the beloved Greenpoint eatery &amp;mdash; which previously shut its doors due to the pandemic &amp;mdash; up and running.</description></item></channel></rss>